<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>yocto on Yair Gadelov Tech Blog</title><link>https://yairgd.github.io/tags/yocto/</link><description>Recent content in yocto on Yair Gadelov Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yairgd.github.io/tags/yocto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>install linux on microzed board</title><link>https://yairgd.github.io/2020/08/install-linux-on-microzed-board/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yairgd.github.io/2020/08/install-linux-on-microzed-board/</guid><description>The microzed developmnet board has zilinx zynq7000 chip. It has application proccess unit with cortex a9 and FPGA fabric. The board also contains interfaces like SDIO and QSPI. I want to install linux on it directly with yocto and without petalinux, which runs yocto behind the scene so I tried to eliminate the need of using it. why to so ?
It is intersting and I have alot of experiance with yocto an it very easy to work with its script once you know it work the same as other proccessos: IMX , stm32Mp157 etc&amp;rsquo; using build tools like cmake,autotools and yocto script make it very easy to port SW between different proccessors.</description></item><item><title>Custom opkg repository</title><link>https://yairgd.github.io/2020/06/custom-opkg-repository/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yairgd.github.io/2020/06/custom-opkg-repository/</guid><description>The post presenst simple example to create opkg repository to upgrade embbded linux systems using nginx server. The opkg pakcge should be installed as part of the image furing the first instalation. To add opkg to yocto image type type folloing line in file conf/local.conf
IMAGE_INSTALL_append = &amp;#34; opkg \ &amp;#34; downlad and install opkg utils:
git clone git://git.yoctoproject.org/opkg-utils and create Packages.gz file:
cd /path-to-yocto-build/build/tmp/deploy/ipk ~/opkg-utils/opkg-make-index . &amp;gt; Packages.gz install nginx I haved used gentoo system , so inorder to install nginx on gentoo type:</description></item><item><title>Install Yocto and kernel development tools of IMX8</title><link>https://yairgd.github.io/2020/02/install-yocto-and-kernel-development-tools-of-imx8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yairgd.github.io/2020/02/install-yocto-and-kernel-development-tools-of-imx8/</guid><description>The GCC toolchain and kernel installation. The purpose of this post is to show the installation process of development tools for imx8m-var-dart, which is SOM made by Variscite. Usually, a kernel, userspace applications, and toolchain built as part of a Yocto image but, for continuous development purposes, when custom kernel modules or userspace applications developed, it is more comfortable with making it stand-alone and working on it outside the Yocto image.</description></item></channel></rss>